pharmdaily.com 2013-08-06

# PrivacyPolicy | Disclaimer

**Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy ("Policy") discloses the data collection and use practices of Pharmdaily ("Pharmdaily") in connection with the Pharmdaily Web site (the "Web Site") and all associated Pharmdaily products and services (the "Pharmdaily Services").

Pharmdaily will not directly inform you of any changes to the privacy policy which involve use of your personal information. If at anytime you are dissatisfied with our service to you or are in disagreement with our terms and conditions or privacy policy, you reserve the option to Opt-out of our website and future communication. Pharmdaily may make non-significant changes to our privacy policy and may not notify our members if said changes do not pertain to the handling of personal information.

**What Information We Collect/How We Use It**

We store and use the information you give us in accordance with the terms of this Policy. Our registration form (or registration information you provide our marketing partners if you joined Pharmdaily though one of our partners) requests that you provide certain contact and profile information. That information includes but may not be limited to: name, address, email address, phone number, gender and birth date. Additional information may include, but not be limited to, health and lifestyle information about you and your family such as marital status and household information (spouse, children, pets, etc.), ethnicity, education, income, occupation, purchasing habits, reading habits, insurance, height, weight, physical and mental health conditions and diseases, symptoms, treatments, medications, medical devices, vitamins, health habits, participation in research surveys and clinical trials.

In addition, we might receive information about you from outside sources and add it to your Pharmdaily membership information. We do this to improve personalization of our services (for example, providing better newsletter content, advertising or special offers that we think will interest you).

We also may collect information such as the identification of the server your computer is logged onto and whether you opened a Pharmdaily e-mail delivered to you. We also may compare our customer list to lists received from other companies, in an effort to avoid sending identical messages to our members. You can add and modify the information you have provided by sending an e-mail to [information@pharmdaily.com](mailto:information@pharmdaily.com) This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it. with your requested changes.

**We use all this information in five ways:**

  * to provide you with personalized information via electronic delivery, telemarketing and/or direct mail. These may include personalized offers from 3rd party sources.
  * to send you targeted advertising via electronic delivery and/or direct mail;
  * to contact you for feedback and surveys via electronic delivery and/or direct mail;
  * to send you general and administrative information about your Pharmdaily membership via electronic delivery and/or direct mail; and
  * to provide your contact information to Pharmdaily marketing partners whose offer(s) you have selected to receive in order for them to send you special offers via electronic delivery, telemarketing and direct mail.

**Agents**

We employ other companies and individuals to perform certain functions on our behalf. These companies and individuals may include but are not limited to pharmaceutical companies and their subsidiaries and affiliates, and manufacturers of food and health-related and consumer-related products and services and their subsidiaries and affiliates. Examples include sending direct and electronic mail, removing duplicate information from customer lists, analyzing data, and providing marketing analysis. These agents have access to member personal information as needed to perform their functions for Pharmdaily.

**Third-party Advertising**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like to be removed from any 3rd party advertising and solicitation through E-mail, telemarketing, or direct mail please send your request to [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy96340%20=%20'remove'%20+%20'@';%20addy96340%20=%20addy96340%20+%20'pharmdaily'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\('%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy96340%20+%20'\\'%3E'\);%20document.write\(addy96340\);%20document.write\('%3C\\/a%3E'\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20email%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it.%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3C/'\);%20document.write\('span%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E)[remove@pharmdaily.com](mailto:remove@pharmdaily.com)

To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertising.org.  Additionally, to opt out of any behavioral advertising, you may go here to access and control your anonymous information:   
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

**Cookies**

We use cookies on the site to deliver personalized content. Many Web browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. You may change your browser settings to either reject cookies or notify you when a cookie is about to be placed on your computer. Please note, however, that rejecting cookies while visiting the Pharmdaily Web Site may result in certain parts of the Pharmdaily Web Site not operating correctly or as efficiently as if they were allowed.

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous.

To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertising.org.  Additionally, to opt out of any behavioral advertising, you may go here to access and control your anonymous information:   
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

**E-mail Links**

In some instances we may include certain links in our e-mails that will allow us to monitor whether you access specific content or advertisements contained in that e-mail. When you click on one of these links, we will record that click and certain activities on the Web page associated with that link. We may use this information for various purposes, such as to conduct internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior in and to our e-mail advertisements and content, and to better understand and serve you.

**Disclosures**

Pharmdaily may disclose information about you and your use of the Pharmdaily Web Site and the Pharmdaily Services if Pharmdaily believes such disclosure is reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with the law or legal process; (ii) to protect or defend the rights or property of Pharmdaily or others; (iii) to enforce the Pharmdaily Terms and Conditions or this Privacy Policy; and (iv) to respond to claims that the content(s) of a communication violates the rights of another. In addition Pharmdaily may share or transfer information about you and that you provide to Pharmdaily, to one or more third party entities pursuant to a sale, merger, assignment, joint venture or other transfer or disposition of a portion, or all of, the assets or stock of Pharmdaily or its affiliated entities, or as otherwise provided herein.

**Reports**

We periodically prepare analyses and reports reflecting visitor and member use of the Pharmdaily Web Site and Pharmdaily Service for our internal use as well as for a limited number of our business partners. These reports include aggregate (non-personal) information about Pharmdaily members, and in certain instances, visitors to the Pharmdaily Web Site. The information in these reports will not identify you individually. Our business partners who have access to these reports will not be able to contact you from the information contained in the reports.

**Links**

The Pharmdaily Web Site, as well as the electronic messages sent as part of the Pharmdaily Service, may contain links to other sites or services. Pharmdaily is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third party sites. If you have a question about the privacy policy of those other sites, please contact them directly.

**Removal**

To have all of your personally identifiable information removed from our database, send an e-mail request to [remove@pharmdaily.com](mailto:remove@pharmdaily.com) This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it. and we will be happy to delete such information after we receive a request to that effect. Please be advised that by requesting that your data be removed from our database, you will be unsubscribed from the Pharmdaily Service.

To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertising.org.  Additionally, to opt out of any behavioral advertising, you may go here to access and control your anonymous information:   
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

**Updates**

Pharmdaily may revise this Policy from time to time and at any time in the future to (i) improve or modify the Pharmdaily Service, (ii) reflect future developments in Pharmdaily data information gathering, storing and release practices, (iii) comply with applicable laws, and (iv) reflect changes in Pharmdaily business structure. Depending on the nature of the change, we will notify users by e-mail (to the current e-mail address on file) and/or placing a notice on the Pharmdaily Web Site.

If you do not accept the terms of this Policy, we ask that you do not register with Pharmdaily, or with any of our promotional partners.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:  
PharmDaily  
2232 South Nellis Blvd.,  
Suite G 3 #311 Las Vegas, Nevada 89104  
e: [information@pharmdaily.com](mailto:information@pharmdaily.com)
